亲爱的
Hey, honey.
正好赶上吃早饭了
Oh, you're just in time for breakfast.
我们也许应该少吃点
Ooh, we should probably go light on the food.
直觉告诉我
Something tells me we're
撑着肚子去会不舒服的
not gonna want to do this on a full stomach.
不敢相信居然真的有尸检夏令营这种东西
I can't believe there's such a thing as autopsy camp.
根本没什么尸检夏令营
There is no such thing as autopsy camp.
我不得不骗卢克
I had to trick Luke
因为我其实是要带他去上交谊舞课
'cause I'm actually taking him to a ballroom-dance class.
他一直很抗拒
He's been resisting,
但他流淌着舞蹈家的血液
but it's in his blood.
我们邓菲家族舞蹈家辈出
I come from a long line of dancing Dunphys --
其实都是啦啦队的
A kick line, actually.
快点  我们可别晚了[救不活]
Come on, we don't want to be late,
像那个我们将看到的解剖台上的家伙
like the guy we're gonna see on the table.
我说得没错吧
Am I right?
确"尸"没错
Of corpse you are.
老妈  你能带我去练车吗
Hey, mom, can you take me driving?
我快考试了  我真的得好好练练
My test is coming up, and I really need to practice.
亲爱的  我也想
Oh, honey, I would,
但我今天有个很重要的
but I've got a big
橱柜和百叶窗协会会议
closets and blinds union meeting today.
根本没什么橱柜和百叶窗协会
There is no closets and blinds union.
跟艾丽克斯一起开车绝对是种折磨
Driving with Alex is torture.
她开得太慢了
She drives so slowly.
全世界可能只有我这个家长
I have to be the only parent
需要狂踩假想的油门
who slams on the imaginary gas.
我没什么事  可以带她练车
Hey, I'm not doing anything. I guess I could take her.
太棒了  我去检查胎压和油液位
Great! I'll go check the tire pressure and the fluid levels!
有意思  迫不及待了
Fun! Can't wait!
我马上就来
Be out in a sec!
好了  我提价了
Okay, my rate just went up.
好  但这钱既是酬劳也是封口费
All right, but this buys your time and your silence.
不能让艾丽克斯知道我有多讨厌陪她练车
Alex can never know how much I hate driving with her.
她今天倒是很急啊
Mm, she's in a hurry today.
那只是她九步安全测试的第一步
Oh, that's just step one of her nine-point safety test.
第二步是检查喇叭
Step two is checking the horn
确保检查喇叭没有搞坏喇叭
to make sure checking the horn didn't break the horn.
她就不该开车
She should never drive.
■
m 20 0 l 209 0 b 218 0 229 11 229 20 l 229 209 b 229 218 218 228 209 228 l 20 228 b 11 228 0 218 0 209 l 0 20 b 0 11 11 0 20 0
m 115 64 l 115 35 l 171 0 l 177 0 l 133 46 l 143 52 l 179 0 l 184 0 l 159 63 l 229 107 l 229 182 l 145 96 l 135 122 l 207 227 l 137 227 l 115 172 l 115 93 l 126 76 l 115 64 l 104 76 l 115 93 l 115 172 l 93 227 l 23 227 l 95 122 l 84 96 l 0 182 l 0 107 l 70 63 l 45 0 l 50 0 l 87 52 l 97 46 l 52 0 l 59 0 l 115 35
m 71 60 b 71 0 161 0 161 60 b 161 120 71 120 71 60
m 325 0 l 355 0 l 332 47 l 354 47 l 399 136 l 369 136 l 328 53 l 288 136 l 257 136 l 325 0 m 467 0 l 497 0 l 474 47 l 496 47 l 541 136 l 511 136 l 470 53 l 430 136 l 399 136 l 467 0 m 545 1 l 583 1 l 583 14 l 568 14 l 568 19 l 583 19 l 583 30 l 568 30 l 568 34 l 599 34 l 599 30 l 583 30 l 583 19 l 599 19 l 599 14 l 583 14 l 583 1 l 611 1 b 616 1 622 6 622 10 l 622 36 l 652 0 l 678 0 l 644 41 l 622 41 l 622 47 l 596 47 l 597 54 l 625 54 l 625 68 l 541 68 l 541 54 l 572 54 l 571 47 l 545 47 l 545 1 m 583 72 l 583 85 l 569 85 l 569 90 l 598 90 l 598 85 l 583 85 l 583 72 l 611 72 b 615 72 621 78 621 82 l 653 44 l 678 44 l 644 86 l 621 86 l 621 103 l 597 103 l 597 136 l 570 136 l 564 126 l 562 136 l 542 136 l 548 107 l 568 107 l 565 121 l 571 121 l 571 103 l 547 103 l 547 72 l 583 72 m 600 107 l 620 107 l 624 124 l 653 89 l 679 89 l 642 136 l 615 136 l 618 132 l 606 132 l 600 107 m 689 0 l 716 0 l 721 15 l 732 15 l 732 30 l 718 56 l 731 56 l 735 100 l 721 100 l 717 59 l 714 64 l 714 136 l 693 136 l 693 79 l 676 79 l 707 30 l 679 30 l 679 15 l 694 15 l 689 0 m 738 0 l 804 0 b 807 0 813 6 813 9 l 813 87 l 794 87 l 794 14 l 756 14 l 756 87 l 763 77 l 763 21 l 787 21 l 787 91 l 798 91 l 798 120 l 820 120 l 812 136 l 778 136 l 778 90 l 748 136 l 723 136 l 756 87 l 738 87 l 738 0 m 257 151 l 275 151 l 297 182 l 319 151 l 337 151 l 304 197 l 304 227 l 290 227 l 290 197 l 257 151 m 337 151 l 355 151 l 377 182 l 399 151 l 417 151 l 384 197 l 384 227 l 370 227 l 370 197 l 337 151 m 425 192 l 447 192 b 445 181 427 181 425 192 l 410 192 b 414 162 458 162 462 192 l 462 206 l 425 206 b 425 210 429 212 433 213 l 462 213 l 462 227 l 433 227 b 412 227 408 203 410 192 m 462 151 l 532 151 l 532 165 l 504 165 l 504 227 l 489 227 l 489 165 l 462 165 l 462 151 m 580 172 l 580 186 l 549 186 b 543 186 543 192 549 192 l 565 192 b 589 192 589 227 565 227 l 532 227 l 532 213 l 565 213 b 570 213 570 206 565 206 l 549 206 b 524 206 524 172 549 172 l 580 172 m 592 213 l 606 213 l 606 227 l 592 227 l 592 213 m 639 172 l 665 172 l 665 186 l 639 186 b 623 186 623 213 639 213 l 665 213 l 665 227 l 639 227 b 603 227 603 172 639 172 m 700 184 b 722 184 722 215 700 215 l 700 229 b 740 229 740 170 700 170 b 660 170 660 229 700 229 l 700 215 b 680 215 680 184 700 184 m 737 172 l 782 172 b 803 172 813 177 813 198 l 813 228 l 799 228 l 799 198 b 799 186 793 187 782 187 l 782 228 l 768 228 l 768 187 l 752 187 l 752 228 l 737 228 l 737 172
本字幕由人人影视字幕组翻译
禁止用作任何商业盈利行为
翻译：小饭  罂粟无果  慕秋雪  王大可  四方虾  丁小七
时间轴：加森  浓子    校对：olivia_xuxu   后期&总监：瓜瓜
摩  登
家  庭
第五季 第十一集
别想了  你耍了我
Forget it! You tricked me!
很抱歉  伙计  但我的儿子
I'm sorry, buddy, but no son of mine's
可不能上了高中都不知道
going to high school without at least knowing
怎么跳方形步
how to do a proper box step.
相信我  会跳舞的人总能钓到妹子
Trust me, dancers always get the girls.
还记得《浑身是劲》里那个
Remember the great Kevin Bacon
很厉害的凯文・培根吗
from "Footloose"?
我看是"浑身傻劲"吧
More like "Footloser."
注意点
Careful!
好了  废话少说  必须去学
All right, no more talking. We're doing this.
有一天你会感激我的
You'll thank me someday.
等你找到自己的标志性舞步后就好多了
It gets better when you find your signature move!
他们以前总叫我"下腰之王"[扒手之王]
They used to call me "King of the dips"!
昨晚曼尼的派对剩下的东西
Why can't we just repurpose some of the stuff
怎么不能重复利用呢
from manny's party last night?
我们还剩半个蛋糕
We got half a cake left.
气球都完好无损
The balloons are fine.
我的两个儿子
It's bad enough that both my sons
同一天生日已经够糟了
have to share the same birthday.
他们至少得有自己的生日派对吧
At least they deserve their own party.
你觉得乔会介意吃昨天的蛋糕吗
You think Joe's gonna mind day-old cake?
他都吃不了  才长了三颗牙
He can't even eat it. He's got three teeth.
20年后你想吃蛋糕的时候
I'll remember that in 20 years
我一定不会忘了这话
when you want cake.
他都不知道派对是为他举办的
He doesn't even know the party's for him.
他懂的比你想象的多
He understands more than you think.
是吧  安迪
Right, Andy?
谁  乔老弟吗  他聪明得很
Who, F-Jo here? He is smart as a whip.
我们玩躲猫猫  他一半时候比我快
When we play peek-a-boo, half the time he's ahead of me.
又不是《诸神之战》
Not exactly "Clash of the Titans."
曼尼  那是谁的外套
Manny, whose coat is that?
昨晚派对结束后艾米・马丁落在这儿的
Amy Martin left it here last night after my party.
我昨晚收到了她发出的强烈信号
I was getting some pretty strong signals from her.
我觉得她是故意落下的
I think she did it on purpose
这样她就有借口再回来
so she'd have an excuse to come back.
又或者是因为她恨不得尽早脱身
Or because she couldn't get out fast enough.
如果她是卡通人物
If she was a cartoon,
早就把她的皮囊留在这儿跑路了
she'd have left her skin here.
这话什么意思
What does that mean?
意思是他高攀不上艾米
That Amy is out of his league.
他总是这样  最终以受伤收场
He always does this and ends up getting hurt.
-你得跟他谈谈  -该说什么
- You need to talk to him. - And say what?
告诉他追他有机会追到的女孩
Tell him to go for girls he stands a chance with.
我偷听到了他跟罗本的谈话
I overheard him talking to Reuben.
有个女孩真的很喜欢他
There's some girl that really likes him,
但曼尼对人家没兴趣
but of course Manny's not interested in her.
他非要追啦啦队长
He's got to go for the head cheerleader.
你怎么知道艾米是啦啦队长
How do you know that Amy's the head cheerleader?
这也是我偷听到的
I overheard that, too.
你这个看电影时经常要问
For someone whose favorite words at the movies
"他刚刚说什么"的人
are, "What did he say?"
倒是偷听得很清楚啊
you overhear pretty good.
没错  莉莉  我拉钩发誓
Yes, Lily, I-I pinky-promise
我们会赶回家参加乔的生日派对
that we'll be home in time for baby Joe's party.
是啊  我在跟手机拉钩啦
I am. I'm touching to the phone.
是啊  还有蝴蝶之吻[用睫毛刷对方脸颊]
Yeah, and butterfly kisses.
好了  好了
Okay, okay.
小女孩  容易激动
Little girls -- so excitable.
我正期望能有个露台  结果他们真的有
I was wishing they had a gazebo, and then they did!
我从小时候起就在梦想着
Ever since I was a little boy, I have dreamed --
梦想着在这样一个地方结婚
dreamed of getting married in a place exactly like this.
你们想在什么日子举行婚礼
So, what date were you looking at?
3月28日
March 28th.
那是我们第一次约会的纪念日
That's the anniversary of our first date.
等等  抱歉  请问这是每人的价格吗
Oh, wait, um, I'm sorry. Is this price per person?
是的  不包括酒水  蛋糕和伴奏
Yes, excluding alcohol, cake, and music.
这是什么  门诺派教徒套餐吗
What's that -- the Mennonite package?
你会发现我们的价格是很有竞争力的
I think you'll find our prices are competitive.
我已经准备好签字了
Well, I'm ready to commit.
小卡  小卡
Cam, Cam.
抱歉
I'm sorry.
能  能等我们一会儿吗
Can -- can we have a moment, please?
好  但愿他不是到了最后时刻想悔婚
Okay, well, let's hope he's not having any last-minute jitters.
你不是要在最后时刻悔婚吧
You're not having last-minute jitters, are you?
不  不  但那真是一大笔钱
No, no, but it's a really large deposit,
我想确定一下
and I want to make sure
我们是否真的选定这个地方了
that we're absolutely certain about this place.
我很确定
Well, I'm certain,
所有可行的地方我们都看过了
and we've looked at every possible venue.
而且目前胡娇对这里的点评
And Pepper was by far the least snarky
是最不尖酸的了
about this one.
那倒是
That's true.
他是不会轻易说出"还行"这种字眼的
He doesn't throw the word "Adequate" around lightly.
-好的  就定这里了  -好的
- Okay, okay, it's this place. - Okay.
但是不要表现得这么兴奋好吗
But stop being so excited, all right?
我们或许还能杀杀价
We might be able to get the price down a little bit.
好的  好的  冷面无情  冷面无情
Okay, okay, poker face, poker face.
-现在把语气情绪去掉  -冷语无情
- Yeah, now work on your poker voice. - Poker voice.
好的  我们确实喜欢这里
So, we do like it.
但还算不上钟爱
We're just not sure that we love it.
是  还不算钟爱
Yeah, we're not sure we love it.
那真让我松口气
Oh, that's a relief
因为刚有人打来电话
because someone just called.
-那个房间已经订出去了  -什么
- The room is booked. - What?!
不不不  等等
No, no, no! Okay, wait,
你是要采取强硬手段吗
are you playing hardball?
因为我们这是在采取强硬手段
Because we're playing hardball, too!
我们爱死这里了
We love it!
对不起
Oh, s-sorry.
有位打算庆祝16岁生日的女孩
A young lady planning a sweet 16
刚刚订下了你们的日期
just booked your date.
下一个可预订日期还要等上...
After that, we don't have another opening for...
-两个月  -不
- two months. - No.
不  必须是我们周年纪念日那天
No, it has to be on our anniversary.
等等  那房间是特蕾西・麦考伊订的吗
Wait, did Tracy Mccoy book this room?
特蕾西・麦考伊是我的学生
Tracy Mccoy's a student of mine.
好  我可能有个计划
Okay, I may have a plan.
我绝不接受把婚礼和"饥饿游戏"主题的
I am not having a wedding/"Hunger games"-themed
甜蜜16岁派对搞在一起
sweet 16 par--
你在敲手指头
oh, you're tapping your fingers.
你还真有计划了
You really do have a plan.
某人闻起来很香啊
Well, somebody smells good.
那是什么香水
What perfume is that?
各种香水都有
Every perfume!
上帝只造出了20个浑身臭汗
20 of the sweatiest, geekiest girls
古怪至极的女生用来污染地球
God ever fouled this planet with
而我一个汉子和她们每一个跳了舞
and just me dancing with all of them!
跳摇摆舞的时候
During the charleston,
我的头发还缠在了一个女生的牙套上
my hair got caught in one of their headgear!
第一次上课就跳摇摆舞啦
Wow, Charleston on the first day?
这是最后一次
Last day!
不能因为你会跳舞
Just because you're a dancer
就非得让我也去跳舞  恰恰恰
doesn't mean I have to be one, too, cha cha cha.
该死
Damn it!
我再也不会被你的谎话欺骗了
I'm never gonna fall for one of your lies again.
快带我去参加尸检夏令营
Just take me to autopsy camp.
糟糕  我该不会是要接罚单了吧
Oh, shoot. Am I gonna get a ticket?
要是世间有正气
If there's any justice,
应该让你接上一二三四张
it'll be a big one, two, three, and four.
该死
Damn it!
请出示驾驶证和汽车行驶证  谢谢
License and registration, please.
好的  给你
Absolutely. There you are.
你知道你有个尾灯坏了吗
You know one of your taillights is out?
不  我没注意  真是不小心啊
No, I did not. What a ding-dong!
在这里等着
Wait right here.
好的  我们就在这里等着
Will do. We'll be right here.
这是你对我说谎的惩罚
This is what you get for lying to me.
我有什么办法  我以前说什么你都接受
What choice did I have? You used to be up for anything.
现在不管我提出什么建议  你都反对
Now, no matter what I suggest, it's no, no, no.
这就叫长大成人  有自己的兴趣爱好
It's called growing up and having your own interests,
像你爱看的《浑身是劲》里
like the minister's daughter
那个大臣之女一样
in your precious "Footloose."
竟然用我爱看的电影来驳斥我
Wow, using my own movie against me.
来给这孩子鼓鼓掌吧
Let's hear it for the boy.
请下车
Please step out of the car.
我相信汽车尾灯坏了  不用下车看
Oh, I believe you about the taillight.
-下车  -好吧
- Out of the car! - Okay.
抱歉  但我得逮捕你
I'm sorry, but I have to place you under arrest.
等等  你说什么
Wait, what?!
你名下有一辆汽车
A car registered to you
累计有18次违规停车未付罚金
has accumulated 18 unpaid parking violations...
都是占用校内车道
all on campus drive.
我的天  那都是我女儿的罚单
Oh, my god, those are my daughter's tickets!
他为一切负责
He's got an answer for everything.
我得把你带到局里去
I got to take you down to the station house.
你可以坐在副驾驶
You can ride up front with me.
说真的  我不能直接把罚款交给你吗
Seriously, can't I just pay you for them now?!
先生  你得去局里交
At the station house, sir.
我们可以至少绕开中土漫画店
Can we at least not drive by middle earth comics
和蹦床世界吗
and trampoline world?!
这里的人民是很敬仰我的
People look up to me in this town!
不  亲爱的  卢克没事
No, honey, Luke's fine.
他们不接受信用卡吗
And they won't take a credit card?
不接受  1600元  只收现金
No, it's $1,600, cash only.
可是  亲爱的  今天是周日
But, honey, it's Sunday.
我在自动提款机上只能提几百块钱
I can only get a few hundred bucks from the ATM.
先生  您的通话时间到了
Sir, your time's up.
亲爱的  使用应急现金吧
Honey, just use the emergency cash, okay?
-时间到  -可是  菲尔
- Tick-Tock. -Uh, b-but, Phil --
-我得挂了  -不  亲爱的
- Got to go! - No, honey --
藏钱的地方我忘了  菲尔
I forgot the hiding place! Phil?
菲尔在家里藏了一千块钱
Phil has $1,000 hidden in the house,
他还编了一套疯狂的助记法
and he's made up a crazy mnemonic device
用于记住藏钱的地点
to remember the location,
他每个月都会变换藏钱的地点来防备坏人
which he changes every month to stay ahead of the bad guys.
哪有什么坏人
What bad guys?
搜刮的刮和傻瓜的瓜音似
"Loot" rhymes with "Coot,"
会把我们带到
which takes us to...
你祖父的这张照片
this picture of your grandfather.
钞票的票比较像飘飘的飘
"Moola" sounds like "Coola."
这算个词吗
Not a word.
钱就藏在空调的通风口
Money is in the air-conditioning vent.
这件事马上就能解决了  伙计
This will all be over soon, buddy.
最后再给我笑一个
Just give me one last smile!
你也笑一个
You too.
你妈已经带着钱上路了  别担心
Mom's already on her way with the money, okay? Don't worry!
上帝啊  我不想进那里
Oh, my god, I don't want to go in there!
你要进的是这里
You're going in here.
我也不想进这里
I don't want to go in here!
好了  这是索菲工作的地方
Okay. This is where Sophie works.
她是戴帽子的那个女孩儿
She's the one in the hat.
-明白  -特蕾西在楼上工作
- Copy that. - Tracy works upstairs.
我们半小时后美食街见  怎么样
We'll meet in the food court in 30 minutes. Sound like a plan?
还行  不确定是敲着手指想出来的计划
A plan, not sure if it's a finger-drumming plan.
快过去吧
Get in there.
我的两个学生  特蕾西和索菲是闺蜜
Two of my students, Tracy and Sophie, BFFs,
原本计划一起举办甜蜜16岁生日派对
were planning on having a joint sweet 16 together
但她们为了一个叫罗德尼的男生争风吃醋
until they got in a fight over a boy, Rodney.
现在特蕾西计划在马车房
Now Tracy is planning on having her own party
举办她自己的派对
at the carriage house.
那是我们的位置  我们的日子
Our venue, our date.
所以我们的办法是跟两人谈话让她们和好
So, our solution -- talk to them, patch things up
这样她们就能在原定地点
so that they have their party together again
一起办派对了
at the original location.
朋友间为了男孩子争风吃醋
Friends fighting over a boy --
对付这种事我们还是略知一二的
something we know a thing or two about.
当然通常都是男同志们  而不是少女们
Of course, usually it's gay men, not teenage girls,
所以我们对策略的改变是  丝毫不变
so we will have to adjust our approach just a -- not at all.
我不知道
I don't know.
需要帮忙吗
Uh, may I help you?
是的  索菲
Mm, yeah, uh, Sophie.
我想给我侄女买点儿东西
Um, I'm looking for something for my niece.
她最近很不开心
She's been really bummed out lately --
跟最好的朋友吵架了  所以我
fight with her best friend -- so I'm just --
我想让她高兴起来
I'm trying to cheer her up.
你真好
That's so nice.
是啊  她总跟我说
Yeah, she's always saying to me,
米奇叔叔  你真酷  又那么时髦
"Uncle Mitch, you're so cool. You're so rad.
我真喜欢跟你讨论我的问题
I'm so glad I talk to you about my problems."
我就是很了解那个年纪的孩子
You know, I just -- I really get kids that age.
她  她快到16岁了
You know, she's -- she's almost 16, so...
我也快到16岁了
I'm almost 16.
太巧了
Crazy.
特蕾西
Tracy?
特蕾西・麦考伊
Tracy McCoy?
塔克老师  你好啊
Mr. Tucker, hi.
我都不知道你已经到了可以工作的年龄了
I didn't know you were old enough to have a job.
我直到16岁才有了份工作
I didn't have a job until I was 16.
我就快到16岁了
Well, I'm almost 16, so...
真的啊
Crazy!
我的天啊  我还记得那个时候
Oh, my gosh, I remember back then.
我和我的朋友们过得特别开心
My friends and I had so much fun,
如果我们没有为了一些愚蠢的事情
well, when we weren't arguing
争吵的话  比如派对还有...
about silly things like parties and...
行了  镜子看得够多了
Okay, that's a lot of mirror looking,
我这么爱照镜子的人都嫌多
and that's me saying that.
很好  很好
Good, good.
这巡航速度真不错
Nice cruising speed.
看啊  那有个慢跑的人
Oh, look, there's that jogger.
我们现在在领跑呢
Now we're in the lead.
讽刺挖苦这件事上你能踩下刹车吗
Can we put the brakes on the sarcasm?
刹车早被踩坏了
They're worn out.
喂  妈
Hey, mom.
海莉  你给我听着
Haley, listen to me.
因为你有一堆停车罚单没按时交罚款
You did not pay a bunch of parking tickets,
你爸现在进监狱了
and now your father is in jail.
而我得去把他保释出来
And I have to go bail him out
但我得先找到一大笔现金
just as soon as I can get my hands on a giant pile of cash.
现金  灰烬
Cash -- ash!
天啊
Oh! Oh, god.
好多绒毛
Oh! That was furry!
你惹上大麻烦了
You are in so much trouble.
你觉得我不知道吗
Oh, don't you think I know that?!
我该怎么办
What am I gonna do?!
你会得到应有的惩罚
You're going to get what you deserve.
停车违规仅次于行车违规
A parking violation is second only to a moving violation,
行车违规会被剥夺驾驶特权
which is grounds for the loss of a driving privilege.
是特权  不是普通权利
Privilege, not a right.
天啊  你闭嘴吧
Oh, my god, shut up!
这就是为什么妈付我钱给你做陪驾
This is why mom pays me to drive with you!
什么
What?
你以为她是从哪里打来的电话
Where do you think she's calling me from --
衣柜和盲人协会吗
the closet and blinds union?
[Blinds有"百叶窗"和"盲人"两个意思]
造衣柜的工人和盲人怎么会
Why would closet workers and blind people
在一起办协会
even have a union together?!
用脑子想想吧
Think!
打扰一下  服务生
Excuse me, waiter.
能给我介绍一下海鲜牛排套餐吗
Could you please tell me about the surf and turf?
龙虾先生说
Mr. Lobster says...
特别难吃
"It's terrible!"
而牛说
While Mr. Cow goes...
我觉得你还是吃意大利面吧
"I think you should probably just have the pasta."
爸爸
Dada.
不  不  不对  宝宝
No, no, no, little man.
在那里喝小酒的才是你爸爸
That's your dada right there with the drinky.
解释过多
Over-explaining.
别难过  他只是在发声
Don't feel bad. He's just making sounds.
他可能都不知道"爸"字是什么意思
He may not even know what the "D" word means.
我没事  他才1岁
I'm fine. He's 1.
我见过他尿到自己的照片上还在笑
I've watched him pee into his own face and smile.
你好啊  亲爱的
Hola, mi amor.
我想跟你聊聊
I wanted to talk to you.
你在干什么
What are you doing?
我打算用我自己的浪漫招数
I decided to top Amy's little "Forgotten Coat" trick
给艾米忘记外套的小花招锦上添花
with a romantic gesture of my own.
你看
You see --
是的  关于艾米
Yes, about Amy...
我知道我不了解她
I know that I don't know her,
可她看起来就像你以前喜欢过的那些女孩
But she seems like some of those girls that you have liked,
可她们基本没有
but they haven't always--
你可能不了解她  但我很了解
You may not know her, but I do.
我去看了她的Facebook页面
I went on her Facebook page,
然后在她大衣的每个口袋里
and I put one of her favorite things
都放了一样她喜欢的东西
in each of the pockets of her coat.
所以当她摸到里面时
So when she reaches inside--
就会发现一小盒荷兰巧克力
she'll find a small box of Dutch chocolates.
很窝心  可是
Sweet, but --
覆盆子狂想曲唇彩  有人想要吗
Raspberry rhapsody lip gloss, anyone?
我的最爱啊  可我还是觉得
My favorite, but I still wonder--
快看  天堂美浴浴盐
Hello, heavenly soak bath salts.
她还会发现什么
What next will she find?!
不过是一支山谷百合幽香烛台
Only a lily of the valley scented candle.
我的大爱
I love it!
真希望她口袋再多点
Oh, I wish she had more pockets!
"美元"跟"臭"音近
"Bucks" rhymes with "Nyuks" --
《三个臭皮匠》
Three Stooges.
混蛋
Damn it!
"皮夹子"  "塑料丝球"
"Wampum," "Pom-pom" --
啦啦队服
Cheerleading costume.
拜托  天呐  真的要这么难么
Come on. Oh, my god, really?
"银行"  "沉船"
"Bank," "Sank" --
《泰坦尼克号》电影的小说版
Novelization of the movie "Titanic."
那我们为什么还要留着这东西
Then why do we keep that thing?!
菲尔  当然了
Oh, Phil, of course!
显然是因为"钱"音近于...
Of course, because "Dough" rhymes with--
管它呢
I don't care.
你好啊  小家伙
Hi, buddy.
我是谁
Who am I?
来吧
Come on.
他是你爸爸
He's your dad.
没错  他是你爸爸
That's right. He's your dad.
你好  爸爸  你好  爸爸
Hi, dad. Hi, dad.
你可以的
You can do it.
加油  叫爸爸
Come on, say, "Dad."
叫呀
Come on.
Come on!
安迪
Andy!
索菲那边进展如何了
Hey. How'd it go with Sophie?
我尽力了  但我觉得她还不能原谅对方
I did my best, but I don't think she's ready to forgive.
该死
Oh, damn it.
是啊  我们完蛋了
I know. We're screwed.
是啊  多亏了索菲的"贡献"
Yeah, thanks a lot, Sophie.
特蕾西确实有点过分了
Well, Tracy really was out of line.
-怪她吗  -是啊
- Was she? - Yeah.
是索菲一如既往太小题大作了吧
Or was Sophie, per usual, being a big drama queen?
小题大作吗
Drama queen?
不  特蕾西还散播谣言
No, Tracy was spreading rumors
说索菲的男友还和玛雅在一起
that Sophie's boyfriend was still into Maya.
那不是谣言
They weren't rumors.
她直接从别人那里听说的
She heard it directly from someone
那人看到玛雅和罗德尼在码头手牵手
who saw Maya and Rodney holding hands at the pier.
小卡  谁看见的啊  是黛娜
Cam, who? Dana!
她的话可信吗
Yeah, like she can be trusted.
简直是艾登事件重演
This is Aidan all over again.
米奇尔  是特蕾西的短信
Mitchell, it's from Tracy.
塔克老师  谢谢你
"Mr.Tucker, thank you.
我和索菲谈过了
"Talked to Sophie.
我们还是会一起办派对
Party's back on."
你不是开玩笑吧
Are you kidding me?
天呐  你真是个天才
Oh, my gosh, you're an evil genius!
你才是  知道吗
You are! You know what?
我觉得特蕾西敢于认错真的很棒  真的
I give Tracy a lot of credit for admitting she was wrong. I do.
是啊  即使错的是索菲
Yeah, even though it was Sophie's fault.
-不  -怎么了
- No! - Hmm? What?
他们还要用我们的会场
They're still using our venue!
不  没搞错吧
No! Are you kidding me?!
-太糟糕了  -真的吗
- This is so frustrating! - Really?
你确定你真是这么想的吗
Are you sure that's how you feel,
还是再给你点时间好好想想
or do you need a little more time to think about it?
貌似你有话想说
Sounds like you're trying to make a point there.
我真惊讶你这么快就反应过来了
Wow, I'm surprised you picked up on that so quick.
是啊  你肯定是在暗示什么
Yeah, you're definitely dancing around something.
我觉得跟速度有关
I feel like it's speed-related.
我们没能订上马车房就是因为
Yeah, we lost the carriage house because you,
你一如既往地
true to form,
不能及时做出决定
couldn't make a timely decision.
我们只是出去讨论了两秒钟
We were out of the room for two second--
"一如既往"是什么意思
What is this "True to form" business?
里奇戴尔路28号院
28 Richdale Road.
天呐  你在跟我开玩笑吗
Oh, my god, are you kidding me?
你在我们的梦想家园面前犹犹豫豫
You hemmed and hawed over our dream house,
现在别人正在属于我们的角落里吃早饭
and now somebody else is eating breakfast in our nook!
我需要一个周末来考虑一下
I needed the weekend!
我从没想像过自己住在牧场
I never saw myself in a ranch!
那拉斯维加斯那次呢
And what about Las Vegas
你无法决定要不要去看表演
when you couldn't quite commit to the show?
不不  别提那件事
No. No, no, don't.
不不  没关系啊
No, no, no, it's fine.
我们可以下次再看
We'll see them next time,
等那只白虎不咬罗伊的时候就去看
just as soon as that tiger un-eats Roy.
我喜欢那个标志
I love the sign!
我不太确定
Uh, I'm not sure.
一开始我觉得用一点鲜艳的颜色
First, I thought just a little accent of color
就可以了  可现在我在考虑加上气球
was all it needed, but now I'm thinking balloons.
杰  你更喜欢哪个
Jay, what do you like better--
色彩[口音]还是气"球"
the accent or the balloons?
遇见你之后  我一直在问自己这问题
I've been asking myself that since I met you.
我可以这么说吗
Can I just say,
我希望自己的恋爱中也有这样风趣的调侃
I want this type of playful banter in my relationship.
去别处说去
As long as you say it someplace else.
真好笑
Good one.
你在干什么  他们马上就到了
What are you doing? They're gonna be here any moment.
我在看曼尼的班级纪念册
I've been combing through Manny's yearbook.
我发现了几个他可能有机会钓到的女孩
I found a few girls he might have a shot with.
你知道丽莎・内格尔脖子以下长什么样吗
Happen to know what Lisa Nagel's like from the neck down?
我没跟他讲你要我说的话
I didn't tell him what you told me to say.
什么  为什么啊
What? Why?
因为他告诉了我艾米来了以后他的打算
Because he told me what he's going to do when Amy comes here,
是个很浪漫的计划
and it's beautiful.
我觉得他成功的机会比你想的要大
I think he has a better chance than you think.
他知道怎么跟女孩子说话
He knows how to talk to girls.
他只知道怎么跟一个女孩子说话
He knows how to talk to a girl
就是你
-- you.
我希望你有他的心脏的近照
I hope you have a recent picture of his heart.
这样碎了以后可以照着拼回去
You're gonna need it putting the pieces back together.
我来开
I'll get it!
你好  曼小尼
Hey, Mandrake.
菲尔  我听说了你被抓的事
Hi, Phil. I heard about jail.
-你还好吗  -挺不容易的
- How are you doing? - It was rough.
在那个冰冷的笼子里
Stayed in that cold cell
等了太久  因为我可爱的...
a lot longer than I needed to thanks to my lovely --
你的助记法太扯了  菲尔
Your system is ridiculous, Phil.
其实很简单
Quite simple, actually!
"钱袋"跟"脑袋"发音很像
"Cheddah" rhymes with "Hedda."
你脑袋枕在什么上边  枕头啊
Where do you rest your head on? Your pilla!
-不是吗  哥们  -我没有哥们
- Help me out, buddy. - I have no buddy.
可是  卢克
But... Luke?
我来开
I'll get it!
你别再想了好不好
Would you please just let it go?
我早就不想了
I did let it go immediately.
你才是那个纠结的人
You're the one who hesitated,
你对待任何事都是这样
like you do with everything.
已经说了一路了
The whole way here.
爸  在你发火之前  我...
Dad, before you get mad, I'm --
"我发火之前"是在几小时之前
Oh, we passed "Before I get mad" hours ago
当我因为你被关单人禁闭的时候
when I was sitting in solitary for your crime!
因为里面没有其他人所以才说单人禁闭
It was only solitary because no one else was in there.
你给海莉钱让她陪我练车
You paid Haley to take me driving?
是的
Uh -- that's right.
海莉都告诉我了
Haley told me everything!
你编造了一个工会
You made up a fake union
就为了不来陪我吗
just so you wouldn't have to be with me?!
艾丽克斯  对不起
Alex, I am so sorry.
海莉  我那么信任你
Haley, I trusted you.
信任这个家里的人没有好下场
Good luck trusting anyone in this family,
尤其是爸爸
especially dad.
通常我带你去参加你原本不愿去的活动时
Usually when I drag you kicking and screaming to something,
过后你都会感谢我
you thank me afterwards.
这次我错了
This time, I was wrong.
他做了什么
What did he do?
他骗我去上舞蹈课
He lied me into a dance class.
卢克  对不起
Luke, I am so sorry.
海莉  你有大麻烦了
Haley, you are in so much trouble!
超大麻烦
So much trouble!
别把这事说成她的错
Stop trying to make this her fault!
什么样的父母会骗他们的小孩
What kind of parents lie to their kids?!
就是  这又是什么教育方式
Yeah, what kind of lesson is that to teach all of this?
我说认真的  有些时候我想
Yeah, seriously, sometimes I want --
你们都不知道事情的真相
Hey, neither one of you knows the whole story.
拜托
Ah, please.
让我告诉他们事实
Let me tell them the truth.
艾丽克斯
Alex, the real reason
妈妈不想教你开车的真正原因
mom doesn't want to teach you to drive
是因为她不希望你拿到驾照
is because she doesn't want you getting your license.
-什么  -仔细想想
- What? - Think about it.
开车载你是妈妈最喜欢的和你共处的时间
Mom driving you around is kind of her favorite time with you.
这是唯一你不在埋头看书
It's the only place where your nose isn't buried in a book
而她可以跟你说上话的地方
and she can actually talk to you.
你拿到的是驾照
Sure, you're getting your license,
她失去的却是女儿
but she's losing her little girl.
妈  这是真的吗
Mom, is that true?
过来
Come here.
爸爸对你撒谎的唯一原因是
And the only reason dad lied to you is...
我能告诉他吗  爸
Should I tell him, dad?
说吧
Fine.
爸爸在大学里是个超级书呆子
Dad was a huge nerd in college.
他约了妈妈快十次都被拒绝了
He asked mom out like 10 times, and she always said no.
最终  他说  只要你做一件事
Finally, he said, "I'll never bug you again
-我就再也不烦你了  -只要一件事
- if you do one thing." - Just one.
-和我跳舞  -只是跳舞
- "Dance with me." - Just dance.
他抱着她在舞池旋转
He spun her around on the floor
用肢体语言表达他无法
and expressed himself with his body
-说出口的情感  -很美好
- in a way he never could with words. - That's beautiful.
妈妈才终于看到了
Mom finally saw the dad
我们深爱的这个爸爸的优点
that we all know and love.
所以你想教会我这招
And you wanted to give that to me?
过来
Come here.
大家过来吃蛋糕啦
Everybody, come for cake!
我们可以晚点再讨论对我的惩罚
We can discuss my punishment later.
她是跟我们学的吗
Did she learn that from us?
那个可学不会  是天份
That can't be taught. It is a gift.
她还是那样
Yeah, she's still doing it,
眼泛桃花地跟着我
following me around all moony-eyed.
她怎么就不明白我的意思呢
She just won't get the message.
不过好消息是  艾米马上就过来了
But on the bright side, Amy's on her way over.
我们得谈谈
We need to talk.
我得挂了  罗本
Got to go, Reuben.
-什么事  -关于你的感情生活
- What's up? - It's about your love life.
有好多人在呢  杰
A lot of people here, Jay.
这是我正式对你进行介入指导
Consider it an intervention.
这个艾米的事有点不太靠谱
Now, this whole Amy thing is going nowhere,
不过听起来有另外一个女孩很喜欢你
but it sounds like you have a girl that really likes you.
我知道这可能不是你最想要的
Now, I know it's not everything you want.
可能她体态有点偏胖
M-maybe she's a little thick in the middle.
我也不知道
I don't know.
可是你何不给她一个机会呢
But why don't you give her a try?
所以你觉得我应该选择那个女生吗
So you think that's the girl I should go for?
很明显她超喜欢你
She's obviously crazy about you.
你了解她别的方面吗
I mean, what else do you even know about her?
你好啊曼尼
Hi, Manny.
她只有六岁而且跟我有血缘关系
Well, she's 6 and related to me.
我还需要继续说吗
Shall I go on?
这倒是解释了今早她为什么
Okay, that explains all the outfits
那么在意自己穿什么
she rejected this morning.
我的观点还是没变
The point remains.
你应该把眼光放低一些
You could lower your sights a little.
好吧  还是要继续这个话题
Good, we're still talking about this.
放过他吧
Ay, leave him alone.
艾米来了一定会喜欢她外套里的惊喜的
When Amy comes, she's going to love her coat surprise.
艾米是谁
Who's Amy?
就是杰认为对我没兴趣的那个女生
This girl Jay doesn't think is into me,
但是她把外套留在这里了
but she left her coat here.
她这么做还有什么别的原因
Why else would a person do that?
这么说的话我爱死丹尼斯餐厅了
By that logic, I love Denny's.
即使她现在不喜欢我
Even if she's not into me right away,
难道以后就没有可能日久生情吗
isn't it possible she could fall for me over time?
没有  有种东西叫化学反应
No, there's a thing called chemistry.
真有感觉的话一下就知道了
People know right away.
也不一定
Not necessarily.
我当时也不知道自己会喜欢你
I didn't know immediately that I liked you.
当然也许不是在一开始就知道
Well, maybe not the first minute.
用了一个月吧
One month.
一个月  天哪
A month? Yikes.
我支持曼尼
I'm with Manny.
有些人会相信自己的直觉
Some people can trust their instincts
然后全身心地投入
and leap in with both feet.
但有些人则需要慢慢来
Others need to take their time.
好吧  小卡想说的是
Okay, what Cam is so subtly implying
他在一开始就知道要和我在一起
is that he knew instantly with me
但我就像往常一样需要时间做决定
while I, as usual, took my sweet time.
但你知道吗
Well, guess what.
其实我从第一眼就认定你了
I knew instantly with you.
怎么样
How about that?
-事实上是我没有  -好吧
- Actually, I didn't. - Okay, well, yes,
如果算上那次糟糕的早午餐
if you count that one disastrous brunch, then --
-两个月吧  -两个月
- two months. - Two months?!
-是啊  -天哪
- Mm-hmm. - Yikes!
我站在杰这边
Well, I'm in the Jay camp.
当你遇到了对的人  一下就知道
When you meet the right person, bang!
我就是这种  多久
That's what happened with -- How long?
六个月
Uh...six months?
六个月  天哪
Six months -- Yikes.
但你那时候都怀...跟我订婚了
But you were preg-- tically engaged to me by then.
转得漂亮  爸爸
Mm, nice save, dad.
等等
Wait a minute.
我以为他邀请你跳舞以后
I thought you fell in love with him
你就爱上他了呢
after he danced with you.
那就是六个月的时候啊
And that was six months in.
你为什么等那么久才邀请我跳舞  菲尔
Why did it take you so long to dance with me, Phil?
我也不知道  克莱尔
I don't know, Claire.
按理说我早该那么做了
You'd think I would've gotten to it by then
因为我们那时都同居了
since we lived together.
对不起  我一直在抱怨你拖慢了进度
I'm sorry. I've been berating you about dragging your feet, and,
但在我们之间的事上
and when it comes to us,
我才是更犹豫不决的人
I'm even more hesitate-y than --
不不  这是好事
No, no, this is great because
这就是说我们的纪念日
that makes our real anniversary
其实比原本以为的要晚两个月
two months later when we were both sure.
我们还是可以在马车房举行婚礼
We can still book the carriage house for our wedding.
天哪  你是在给他们打电话吗
Oh, my gosh, are you calling them?
-是的  -太好了
- Yes! - Yes!
不过  我
Although, I-I am --
-打给他们  -好的
- Call them. - Okay.
所以你那时其实一直跟这个家伙同居
So, you were living with this guy the whole time...
-杰  -多可爱
- Jay! - Aww, how cute!
他想吃蛋糕
He wants cake!
不  不  认真听
No, no, listen, listen, listen!
他在说什么
What's he saying?
-杰  -杰
- Jay. - Jay!
他在说"杰"
He's saying, "Jay"!
他认识我
He knows me!
"杰"这个字比"爸爸"要难说
And that "J" word, that's harder to say than "Dada"!
他真是个天才  过来
He's a genius. Come here.
她来了
She's here!
时机到了  曼尼
This is it, Manny!
把她拿下  伙计
Go get her, buddy!
听着  孩子
Hey, hey, hey, listen, kid.
你之前说有些人需要时间
Y-you might've been right about some people
才能缓过神来也许是对的
needing a little more time before they come around.
你看这小宝贝就是这样的
I mean, look at peanut here.
祝你好运  曼尼
Good luck, Manny.
谢了  杰
Thanks, Jay.
你用了六个月才成功是吧  菲尔
So, it took you six months, huh, Phil?
我能接受六个月
I can do six months.
我会等你的
I'll be here!
我不喜欢这种感觉
I'm not loving this.
他的门还是关着
His door is still closed.
他在里面干什么
What is he doing in there?
我觉得我们都清楚他在里面干什么
I think we both know what he's doing in there.
他都弄了几个小时了
He's been at it for hours.
我年轻的时候也是这样
That's how I was at his age.
他会虚脱的
He's gonna wear himself out.
你应该跟他谈谈
You should talk to him.
我不想让他难为情
I don't want to embarrass him.
-那就先敲门  -你说得对
- So, knock first. - Maybe you're right.
我怕他做得方式不对  把自己弄伤
I don't want him doing it wrong and getting hurt.
卢克
Luke?
我进来了
I'm coming in.
伙计  兄弟
Hey, man. Buddy!
爸爸  快出去
Dad?! Get out of here!
别难为情儿子  这很正常
Don't be embarrassed, son. It's perfectly natural!
出去
Get out!